Guide to the Ronald Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development 2013.023
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 6: Housing Developments and Architectural Projects
  This series includes documentation of architectural projects and design of public spaces, primarily from 1980s and 1990s in New York City. Neighborhoods represented in this series include Bedford-Stuyvesant, East New York, East Flatbush, Harlem, Times Square, and others. Projects include housing for homeless and senior citizen populations, educational facilities, parks, gardens and urban farms.
  - Sub-series 6.1: General
    - 2215 Newkirk, Undated (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Architecture and Racism, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Association for Community Design, 1994-1998 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Association of Black Social Workers, 1985 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Bankers Trust Nonprofit Property Management Excellence Awards Flyer, 1995 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Bedford Stuyvesant Vest Pocket Housing, 1967 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Brooklyn Arms, 1989 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn Gardens, Housing for Homeless, Ambulatory Health Facility, and Vacant Land Use, 1989 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn Photographs -- Vest Pocket Housing, 1970-1990 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Catholic Charities -- Homeless, 1984-1987 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Common Ground Community, Inc. -- Times Square Hotel, 1990-1991 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - East Harlem Block Schools, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - East Harlem Block Schools Proposal, 1989-1990 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - East New York, 1975-1995 (Box 87, Folder 6-7)
    - ENF-CR Nostrand between Church and Linden, 1982 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Erasmus Neighborhood Federation, 1981-1987 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Experimental Housing Allowance Program, 1982-1983 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Far Rockaway -- Ed Remsen, 1985-1986 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Father Panik, Bridgeport, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Father Panik. Hartford, 1987-1988 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Fifth Avenue Committee -- Inclusionary Zoning, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Fifth Avenue Final Copy, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Fifth Avenue Local Development Corporation, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation PRI Discussions, 1985-1987 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Gillman Building, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Goddard Riverside -- 205-207-209 West 85th Street, 1989-1990 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Greenpoint Hospital, 1983-1984 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Habitat for Humanity -- NYC: Building Homes, Building Community Narrated by Susan Sarandon, undated (Box 143, Item 407)
    - Harlem Brownstone Program -- Harlem Urban Development Corporation, City College Architectural Center, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Harlem Brownstone Project, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Harlem Urban Development, 1984-1985 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Hartford, 1984 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Homeless Housing and Assistance Program (HHAP), 1985-1990 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Homesteading, 1984-1985 (Box 89, Folder 7-8)
    - Homesteading Technical Assistance, 1985 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Homeward Bound Interfaith Assembly, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Housing Preservation and Development/Neighborhood Redevelopment Demonstration Program File, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 11)
      Contains two 5 1/2" Floppy Disks
    - Housing Project Financial Management, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Housing, Westchester County, 1960-1969 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Housing with Dignity -- DePaul Residence, undated (Box 142, Item 408)
      VHS. Runtime: 0:12:51
    - Improving Access of Nonprofit Housing Developers to Private Financing -- Ford Report, 1973-1989 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Kingsbridge Armory, 1990s-2010s (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - La Carla Fort Greene Housing, 1980-1981 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Loew's Kings Market Analysis Flatbush, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Loew's Kings Theater, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Loew's Kings Theatre Flatbush, 1980-1985 (Box 90, Folder 7-8)
    - Lower East Side (Loisaida) Charas, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Lower East Side (Loisaida) Charas, 1978-1986 (Box 90, Folder 11-12)
    - Lower East Side (Loisaida) Charas / El Bohio Cultural and Community Center, 2000 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Lower East Side Catholic Area Conference, 1971-1987 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Methodist Hospital of Brooklyn Additions, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Myrtle Avenue and the Golden Key Building, Revitalization and Adaptive Reuse, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - NAP Corporate Income Tax Credits, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - New Housing Initiatives, 1985-1988 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - New York City Council Draft Report Homelessness -- Sydelle Knepper, 1988-1991 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Park Slope Fifth Avenue, 1980-1983 (Box 91, Folder 3-4)
    - PICCED Projects Requiring Architectural Assistance, 1983-1984 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Popeck Gottlieb Building, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Popeck Gottlieb Building, 1989-1991 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Pratt Architecture, undated (Box 138, Item 308)
    - Ron/Harriet Putterman, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Senate Hotel PICCED Project, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Senior Citizen HSG AKA 202, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 9)
      Contains two 3 1/2" Floppy Disks
    - Speaking Commitments, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - UHAB Urban Homesteading Assitance Board, 1996-1997 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Weeksville, 1991-1993 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - The West End Intergenerational Residence -- Under One Roof, undated (Box 138, Item 315)
      VHS. Runtime: 0:15:00
  - Sub-series 6.2: Urban Design and Public Space
    - Birmingham, Alabama, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Broadway Triangle Brooklyn, 2001-2015 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - City Planning Commission Projects -- Parks, Zoning, and Commerce, 1994-1996 (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - Community Gardens and Urban Farms, 1995-1997 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - Cooper Hewitt National Design Museum, 1994-1996 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Cultural Map of Lower Manhattan -- NewVisions DowntownNow, 2002 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Emergency Park Development Program for Bedford-Stuyvesant and Central Brooklyn Area, 1960s (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Institute for Urban Design -- Ann Ferebee, 1995-2003 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Jerome Park Resevoir -- City Lake, undated (Box 143, Item 384)
    - Neighborhood Open Space Coalition, 1998-1999 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Places Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Residential Plazas, 1991-1992 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Small Parks and Community Action, 1966-1967 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - They Paved Paradise, The Fight to Save Upper Van Voorhees Park, undated (Box 143, Item 402)
      VHS. Runtime: 0:17:00
- Series 7: City Planning Commission
  The majority of material in this series reflects Shiffman's tenure on the New York City Planning Commission, to which he was appointed by Mayor David Dinkins. Projects of note considered during this period include the rezoning of Times Square, the redevelopment of Penn Yards as Riverside South, the revitalization of lower Manhattan, and retail and industrial rezoning. This series also includes a limited amount of material documenting Shiffman's interactions with the City Planning Commission before and after his years of service.
  - Chinatown-Manhattan Bridge Area, 1984 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - City Planning -- Adult Entertainment Zone, 1995 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - City Planning -- Adult Establishment Zoning, 1995 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - City Planning -- Adult Uses, 1994 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - City Planning -- Davidson Shopping Center (Caldor), 1992-1995 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - City Planning -- Northern Boulevard KMart, 1994-1995 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - City Planning -- Retail and Industrial Rezoning, 1994 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - City Planning -- Retail and Industrial Zoning Text, 1996 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - City Planning -- Revitalization of Lower Manhattan, 1994 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - City Planning at 40 -- Fair Share Testimonies, 1989-1990 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - City Planning Commision, 1991-1992 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - City Planning Commision -- Zoning, Environment Sub-Committee, 1992 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - City Planning Commission, 1990-1996 (Box 92, Folder 11-12)
  - City Planning Commission Meeting, October 26, 1994 (Box 143, Item 399)
  - City Planning Commission Projects, 1973-1996 (Box 93, Folder 1-10)
  - City Planning Commission Projects, 1994-1996 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - City Planning Commission Publications, 1990-2000 (Box 94, Folder 4-5)
  - City Planning Commission Ron Shiffman, 1990-2002 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Commissioner Shiffman Dissents, 1991-1998 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Community Board #3, Undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Community Food Resource Center -- Letter to Commissioner Shiffman, 1992 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Convention Center, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - David Lowe Letter Regarding Planning Commission and Grand Army Plaza, 1979-2005 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Daycare Lease Renewals, 1986-1990 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Grand Central Subdistrict, 1991-1994 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1988 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - New York City Council -- Fair Share Testimonies, 1990 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Planning Commission Planning and Zoning Report, 1992 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Riverside South, 1992 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Riverside South, Penn Yards -- Trump, 1990-1992 (Box 95, Folder 12-15)
  - Riverside South, Penn Yards -- Trump, 1990-1992 (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
  - Sex Related Businesses in Manhattan, 1994 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Tribeca Zoning and Historic Districts, 1992-1995 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Van Vorhees Park, 1993 (Box 96, Folder 5)
- Series 8: State, Regional and Federal Programs
  Included in this series are materials pertaining to Shiffman and the Pratt Center's work in collaboration with housing and human rights programs in New York state and at the regional and federal levels. Both community organization and government agencies are reflected in this series, including the Center for Community Change, New York Tenants and Neighbors, the New York State Division of Human Rights and Housing and Urban Affairs (HUD). Notable subjects include a proposal to augment environmental impact studies for new developments with human rights impact studies, and federal testimony to HUD and the Urban Development Corporation (now part of the Empire State Development Corporation).
  - Budget Cuts, 1981-1982 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Budget Cuts -- Contract on America, 1995 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Center for Community Change, 1981-1993 (Box 96, Folder 9-10)
  - Center for Community Change -- Miscellaneous, 1985-1992 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Center for Community Change Board Meetings, 1994-1999 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), 1994-1997 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Extracts from the Comprehensive Town and Country Planning Scheme of the Paris District, 1965 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Fannie Mae University -- Community Partnerships, 1998 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Governor's Housing Task Force -- Presidential Task Force on the Long Rage Plan for Pratt Institute, 1988 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Gowanus Expressway TSM Study, 1993 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Housing Preservation and Development -- Ten Year Plan, undated (Box 138, Item 304)
    VHS. Runtime: 0:16:30
  - Human Rights Contracts, 1981-1983 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Low or Moderate Income Housing 119th St Building, 1993 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - National Association of Neighborhoods Bulletin, 1980 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - National Economic Development and Law Center, 1989-1992 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - National Low-Income Housing Coalition, 1984-1993 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - National Neighborhood Coalition, 1989-1993 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 1988-1992 (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - New York State Council on the Arts Grant PICCED 2000 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - New York State Department of Economic Development, 1990 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1986 (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - New York State Division of Human Rights, 1983 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - New York State Division of Human Rights, 1980-1984 (Box 98, Folder 1-2)
  - New York State Energy Research and Development Authority, 1981-1984 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - New York State Government Task Force, 1988-1989 (Box 98, Folder 4-5)
  - New York State Urban Development Corp, 1984-1986 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - New York Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition, 1982-1985 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - New York Tenants and Neighbors, 1995 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - New York Urban Coalition, 1982-1984 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Ownership Transfer Project, 1989 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - President Reagan Tax Proposal, 1985 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Presidential Commission Talk, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Quality Communities Interagency Task Force, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Ron Shiffman Statement Before the Subcommittee on Housing, Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs, 1982 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - State of New York Real Estate Advisory Board, 1986 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - The Assembly State of New York, 1985-1989 (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - The Senate State of New York, 1985-1988 (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce Urban Transportation Planning Memo, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Urban Development Corporation, 1990-1991 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Urban Development Corporation Fair Shair Testimonials, 1990-1995 (Box 99, Folder 3-4)
  - Voucher Experimental Housing Allowance Program (EHAP), 1982 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Vouchers -- Section 8, 1987-1988 (Box 99, Folder 6)
- Series 9: Training and Capacity-Building Programs
  Documented in this series are the wide variety of training and capacity building programs offered by the Pratt Center over the course of its history. This series includes substantial material on the Center's primary training program, the Community Economic Development Internship. Also included are training programs focused on homeless housing, building rehabilitation, and other topics.
  - A Tenant Landlord Partnership in Energy Conservation, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Campus Master Planning Committee -- Higgins Hall / Emerson Hall, 1991-1992 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Center for Community Development and Design, 1982-1983 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Cleveland Training Program, 1984-1988 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Community Development -- Community Service Fellowship Program, Concept Paper, 1992-1995 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Community Economic Development Internship, 1973-1990 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Community Economic Development Internship, 1973-1990 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Community Economic Development Training Project, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Community Service Community Development Fellowship Program, 1992-1993 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Credits Taught, Academic Year Institute Schools, 1989-1990 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - El Hogar / Asylum Hill, 1987 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1989-1993 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Homeless Housing and Assistance Program Training, 1988 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1994-1995 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Housing and Urban Development Community Renaissance Fellows Program, 1996-1997 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Housing Rehabilitation Training Program RFP, 1978-1979 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Internship Practicum Assignment Instructions, 1994 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Negotiating Session #1, 1986 (Box 143, Item 393)
  - Negotiations Training Tape #1 -- Pratt Center for Economic Development, June 10, 1987 (Box 138, Item 301)
  - Negotiations Training Tape #2 -- Pratt Center for Economic Development, June 10, 1987 (Box 138, Item 302)
  - Neighborhood Capacity Building -- Proposal for Housing and Urban Development Contract, 1981-1983 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - New York School for Social Research, 1994-1996 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - PCEDI Interns, 1998 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - PICCED and Pratt Planning Department Joint Training Program, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - PICCED Trainings on Strengthening Organizational Infrastructure, 2002 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - PICCED's Community Development Leadership Education Initiative Meeting #1, undated (Box 143, Item 385)
  - PICCED's Community Development Leadership Education Initiative Meeting #2, undated (Box 138, Item 372)
  - PICCED's Community Development Leadership Education Initiative Meeting #3, undated (Box 143, Item 386)
  - Planning for Change: Pratt Community Economic Development Internship, 1984-2010 (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Pratt Alumni Council, 1991-1993 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Pratt Center Education -- Training in Community Economic Development, 1993-1996 (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
  - Pratt Community Economic Development Internship, 1989-1998 (Box 101, Folder 3-5)
  - Pratt Economic Development Internship, 1990-1992 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Pratt Housing Rehabilitation Training Program, 1978 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Pratt Institute Berlin-Barcelona Study Tour, 2002 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - President Thomas F. Schutte, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Revson Fellowship Dinner, 2002 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - School of Architecture, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - School of Architecture -- Dean Frances Halsband, 1991-1993 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - SEEDCO, 1987-1991 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Shorebank Advisory Services, Inc., 1989 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Sinergia, 1989-1991 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Summer Seminar Part I, 1974 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Summer Seminar Part II, 1974 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Training and Planning for People with Disabilities, 1990-1995 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Training Opportunities for Community Housing Development Corporations, 1996 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Upstate Intern List, 1998 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Weekend Planning Institute Project Workshops, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 11)
- Series 10: Environmental Programs
  This series includes materials on environmental programs developed by Ron Shiffman and the Pratt Center, primarily relating to brownfields and energy conservation. A brownfield is vacant land that was previously used for industrial or commercial purposes, which resulted in soil contamination from hazardous waste. This series documents Shiffman and the Pratt Center's work with European colleagues to develop strategies for remediating contamination and redeveloping these sites. Additional environmental programs reflected in this series include green roofs, solar energy and energy conservation. The majority of materials in this series date from the late 1990s and early 2000s.
  - A Tenant Landlord Partnership in Energy Conservation, 1984 (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Avenue of the Americas Rezoning Final Environmental Impact Statement -- City Planning Commission, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Brownfield Policy and Practice -- Conference Summary Report, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Brownfield Training, 2001-2003 (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Brownfields, 1996-2000 (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - Brownfields, 1996-2000 (Box 103, Folder 1-3)
  - Brownfields -- Duisburg, New York, 1998 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Brownfields and Green Initiatives, 1968-1997 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Brownfields Coalition Bill, 1995-2000 (Box 103, Folder 5-6)
  - Brownfields Economic Redevelopment Initiative, 1996 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Carlton Brown Green Building Case Studies, 2006 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Chelsea 197-a plan, 1996 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - City Environmental Quality Review, 1989 (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - City Heat from the Bottom Up -- Energy Conservation Manual, 1986 (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Clean Water/Clean Air Bond Act, 1997-2000 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Diana Balmori and Associates -- Green Roofs, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Energy Task Force, 1983-1988 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Energy Task Force Solar and Energy Conservation Manual, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Business Association of New York State Inc. -- Green Roofs, 2002-2003 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Justice, 1970 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Justice, 2000-2002 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Pollution Community Renewal, 1994 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Environmentally Sustainable Communities, 1992-2002 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - EPA Brownfield Proposal, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Green Roofs Conference, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Greenpoint/Williamsburg Community Environmental Health, 1989 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Greenpoint/Williamsburg Copies of Photographs, 1970-2010 (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Greenpoint/Williamsburg Right to Know, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Greenpoint/Williamsburg Waterfront, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Long Island Brownfields, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - National Green Industries Policy Retreat, 2008 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - New Roofs New Century Conference, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - New York Lawyers for Public Interest Brownfields, 2000-2003 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - New York SERDA, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - New York State Energy, 1984 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - PICCED Energy Use Issues, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Pocantico Brownfields -- Memos and Emails, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Pocantico Brownfields -- Reports and Drafts, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Pocantico Roundtable for Consensus on Brownfields, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Port City Environmental Issues, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Pratt Sustainable Development Studio, 2006-2007 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Redeveloping Greenpoint's Waterfront Brownfields: A Tool for Communities, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Smart Growth Outlook 2011: Brownfields, Area-Wide Planning, and Implementation (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Sustainable Long Island, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - The Beldon Fund Grant, 2001 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - The Gowanus Canal: Reclaiming Abandoned Infrastructure, 1998 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Urban Development Assistance Grants (UDAG) Review Events, 1979 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Waste Transfer, 1992-1998 (Box 106, Folder 4)
- Series 11: General Correspondence
  This small series includes general correspondence files between Ron Shiffman and collaborators, professional organizations, committees and conferences.
  - Accion Latina, 1982 (Box 107, Folder 20)
  - Advisory Board, 1980-1991 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - Advisory Committee, 1988-1996 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - AIDS Interfaith Residential Services, Inc, 1989 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1983-1989 (Box 108, Folder 5-6)
  - American Planning Association, 1984-1986 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Architects, Designers, Planners for Social Responsibility New York (ADPSR NY), 1991-1992 (Box 107, Folder 21-22)
  - Award Nominations, 1986-1988 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Bellamy, Carol, 1984-1985 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Black Veterans for Social Justice, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Center Admin -- Memos to Staff, 1984-1986 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - City Limits Board Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 108, Folder 21)
  - Collaborative General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - Combatting Abandonment, 1977 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - Community Development Notes, Letters, and Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Computer Proposals, 1988-1989 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Coordinating Council Pratt Coordinating Council, 1987-1990 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Regarding Zoning, Urban Strategies, and Training, 1994 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Various, 2004-2005 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Cuomo's Commission, 1984-1986 (Box 116, Folder 20)
  - Daycare at Pratt, 1982 (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Emmanuel Levy, Cornell Correspondence, 1990 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Foundations and Fundraising, 1978-1995 (Box 106, Folder 9-10)
  - Foundations and Fundraising, 1978-1995 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Grant Seeking Opportunity, 1996-1997 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Greenpoint Video Project, Greentank: An Adaptive Reuse Proposal for the East River Sludge Storage Tank, undated (Box 143, Item 375)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1988 (Box 106, Folder 12)